Finding Aid for the Nicholas E. Baehr Scripts PASC.0234
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nicholas E. Baehr scripts
circa 1950s-circa 1970s
UCLA Library Special Collections
Baehr, Nicholas E.
PASC.0234
0.75 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Nicholas Baehr was a writer whose credits include Matinee Theatre, Dan August, Alias Smith and Jones, and McCloud. The collection includes scripts related to Baehr's writing career.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift, 1986.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9946589463606533
Biography
There is very little biographical information available about Nicholas E. Baehr. He was a writer and appeared to write mostly for television. Among his writing credits are: Armstrong Circle Theatre, Kraft Television Theatre, Matinee Theatre, Dan August, Alias Smith and Jones, and McCloud.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of 17 scripts related to the career of writer Nicholas Baehr. Included are writings for Alias Smith and Jones, Room 222, Delvecchio, and McCloud among other projects.
Organization and Arrangement
The scripts are arranged alphabetically by project title.
Television scripts.; Television writers -- Archives.
- Alias Smith and Jones, no date (Box 1, Folder 5)
  General note
  The Bounty Hunter - script written by Nicholas E. Baehr, from a story by John Thomas James (television).
- Alumni Reunion (The), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Script written by Nicholas S. Baehr.
  Scope and Content
  Episode of Matinee Theatre.
- And a Little Child Shall Lead Them, no date (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Script written by Nicholas E. Baehr. From the Campbell Summer Soundstage series.
- Bounty Hunter (The), no date (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Teleplay by Nicholas E. Baehr. Story by John Thomas James. (Television)
  From the series, Alias Smith and Jones.
- Brahmin, no date (Box 2, Folder 1)
  The Johnson County Invasion - teleplay by Nicholas E. Baehr. Story by John Thomas James.
- Danny Boy, no date (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Script written by Nicholas E. Baehr.
- Delvecchio, 1976 Jan 8 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Look At Any Woman - script written by Nicholas E. Baehr.
- Fitz And Bones, 1980 Nov 28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  An Ordinary Rotten Little Town - script written by Nicholas S. Baehr.
- Gallin, All-American, no date (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Honeymooners (The), no date (Box 1, Folder 7)
  The Five-Year Plan - script written by Nicholas E. Baehr and James Lee. (Television)
- Life of Mickey Mantle (The), no date (Box 1, Folder 12)
- McCloud, 1974 July 31 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  The Tiffany Caper - final revised script written by Nicholas E. Baehr.
- McCloud, 1974 Oct 17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Lady On The Run - script written by Nicholas E. Baehr.
- McCloud, no date (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Three Guns For New York - script
- Nude Scene, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
  From an episode of Bracken's World.
- Palmer Way (The) - A Play In One Act, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Play, written by Nicholas E. Baehr.
- Room 222, no date (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Mr. Bomberg - script written by Nicholas S. Baehr.